"NETFLIX
オリジナルシリーズ"
オープニングテーマ
'New Stranger'
ORIGINAL WORK BY RENSUKE OSHIKIRI
"ハイスコアガール"
♪終業のチャイムで
走り出す ゼロフレーム♪
♪今日も戦いに
飢えた獣とたわむれる♪
♪ずっと画面の端
待ちながら溜め続けた♪
♪情熱の炎が
西の空染める♪
♪陽の当たる
ステージでは見えない♪
♪小さな想い♪
♪今も街のどこかで
輝いている♪
♪心の奥のゲージを
使うのはいつ？♪
♪デタラメと
何度言われたって♪
♪誰にも
認められなくったって♪
♪止まらない止まれない
この勝負は譲れない♪
♪高く弾くコイン♪
♪表と裏 選び取る選択♪
♪教科書に載ってない
答えを探して♪
♪戦いはずっと続く♪
♪もっと高く♪
♪もっと遠くで♪
♪きっといつか♪
♪また出会う♪
♪デタラメと
何度言われたって♪
♪誰にも
認められなくったって♪
♪止まらない止まれない
この勝負は譲れない♪
"1992年"
（男性）
1992年４月
April, 1992.
「ストリートファイター２
ダッシュ」登場
Street Fighter II: Champion Edition
is released.
同年10月「ぷよぷよ」登場
"「ぷよぷよ」"
October of the same year,
Puyo Pop is released.
（声援）
ビル・クリントン侯補
アメリカ大統領選当選
Bill Clinton is elected
as President of the United States.
「ストリートファイター２
ダッシュターボ」登場
Street Fighter II Turbo: Hyper Fighting
is released.
「ストリートファイター２
ダッシュターボ」登場
"「餓狼伝説」"
Fatal Fury 2 is released.
「餓狼伝説(がろうでんせつ)２」登場
（声援）
翌年ビル・クリントン
アメリカ合衆国大統領に就任
The following year, Bill Clinton
is sworn in as President.
「ダークエッジ」登場
Dark Edge is released.
「スーパーストリート
ファイター２」登場
Super Street Fighter II:
The New Challengers is released.
「スーパーストリート
ファイター２」登場
"1993年12月"
そして1993年12月
Next, in December 1993...
ゲーム史上初
ポリゴン格闘ゲーム
The release of the first 3D-polygon
beat-'em-up title in gaming history
Virtua Fighter.
「バーチャファイター」登場
（ゲームの音）
"ROUND 4"
（男子）
あっ！
おい マズイぜ！
Hey, look out!
生活指導の沼田(ぬまた)が
見回りに来てるぜ
That guidance counselor, Numata--
he's doing the rounds!
- あ？
- ウソだろ！
-What?
-You're kidding!
これ１プレー
200円もするんだぞ？
This thing takes 200 yen
for just one go!
まだやり始めた
ばかりなのに…
I just started playing...
Dang it!
くそたれ！
"矢口春雄(やぐち はるお)
中学２年生"
HARUO YAGUCHI
JUNIOR HIGH, YEAR 2
（歩く音）
くそたれー！
This blows!
- 早く早く
- 見つかっちまうぜー！
Come on, hurry!
He'll catch us!
同じクラスの矢口春雄くん
That's Haruo Yaguchi,
from my class.
こんな不良のたまり場
みたいな所に行くなんて
Was he really messing around
at a dump like this?
来年から受験生なのに…
To think, he'll be doing test prep
next year...
Must be nice to be
so carefree.
気ままでいいな
（電車の音）
（歩く音）
- えいっ
- ただいま
I'm back.
おおっ小春(こはる)
Oh, Koharu!
"日高(ひだか)商店"
見ろ ウチもとうとう
ゲーム筐体を導入したぞ！
Take a look!
I finally set up some arcade games.
へぇー
Oh?
けっこう奮発したんだからな
I really went all-out!
Now all the kids will throw
their 50-yen coins in here, non-stop!
これから
じゃんじゃん子供達が
50円を投入しまくるぞ！
不良のたまり場になりそう…
Bet it'll turn into a dump
for delinquents.
それにこんな寒い中外で
ゲームする子なんていないよ
And what kid is going to play
games out here in this cold?
小春も一丁
プレーしてみっか？
-Wanna give it a shot, Koharu?
-No thanks.
いい
（静かな音楽）
（時計の音）
もうすぐ冬休みか
So it's nearly winter break...
クリスマス 正月
Christmas...
New Year's...
すぐ始業式
Then school starts again.
Seems it'll be another
boring end to the year.
今年も退屈な
年末年始になりそう
私 ホントに
遊びの才能ないな
I'm really no good at having fun...
げははは！
矢口くんはいいな
Must be nice being Yaguchi...
He always looks like having fun...
いつも楽しそうで…
（ブルルン）
（先生）
このクラスの人か
分からないけど
I don't know if it was someone
from this class
ゲームセンター等の盛り場で
but I hear some students have been
hanging around that degenerate arcade.
屯してる生徒がいると
聞きました
"天国→行けない
地獄→落ちる"
心当たりがある人は
手を挙げなさい
If you know anything,
raise your hand.
心当たりがある人は
手を挙げなさい
（小春）
よくあんなにシレっと…
He's keeping his cool...
先生
Miss!
矢口くんが駅前のゲーセンに
入り浸ってます
Yaguchi's been sneaking into
the games arcade by the station.
Shimomura, you little--
（タン）
下村(しもむら)てめぇ！
Yaguchi.
矢口くん…
いや 聞いてくれる？
先生
No, Miss, hear me out!
ゲーセンという大人の社会を
垣間見たかっただけなんだ
I wanted to get a glimpse
of adult society at that arcade!
It's true! I was just
studying about society!
そう 社会見学みてぇな
もんなんだよ！
（タン）
"反省文"
LETTER OF APOLOGY
（騒ぐ声）
おい春雄 帰らないのか？
Hey, Haruo!
Not going home?
Gotta write this...
これ書かないとなー
なぁ たまには
俺とも遊んでくれよ
Hang out with me sometime, will you?
さっさと帰れや 宮尾(みやお)
Run along now, Miyao.
そうよそうよ
Yes! Yes!
Run along now, Miyao!
（女子達）
帰ろう 宮尾くん
（女子達）肩を並べてさ
（宮尾）ええー
Shoulder to shoulder...
帰ろー
Home, home...
（タン）
へへ…
やっとみんな帰ったな
Finally! Everyone's gone!
この時を待ってたぜ
I've been waiting for this moment...
（タラーン）
俺のイケナイ野望を
叶えさせてもらう時をよ！
Now I can quench my forbidden thirsts!
お年玉と誕生日の小遣い
合わせてついに買ったこれで
I bought this baby with all the money
I saved from my birthday to New Year's...
And now I can play
Street Fighter II: Champion Edition!
（ゲームの音）
スト２ダッシュだ！
Doing this instead of learning...
Like I'm mocking learning itself!
勉学の場で
勉学を愚弄するが如き行為
Yes, this...
しかしこれが
俺の生き様と言ってもいい！
This is my true calling!
あぁーなんて
素敵な気分なんだ…
Oh, what a wonderful feeling!
教室でソニックブームを
繰り出すこの解放感！
How liberating to sling
a Sonic Boom in the classroom!
- あの…
- ひっ！
-Um...
-What!
ひ 日高！
いたのかよ
Hidaka! You're still here?
教室早く閉めたいんだけど…
I'm about to lock the classroom.
あ そうかお前
今日 日直か…
Ah, that's right, you're on duty today.
あ そうかお前
今日 日直か…
"日直 日高"
学校にゲームボーイ
持ってくる人 初めて見た
It's the first time I've seen
someone bring a Gameboy into school.
違う！
これは「ＰＣエンジンＧＴ」
Wrong!
This is a TurboExpress!
It lets you play
TurboGrafx-16 games on the go!
ＰＣエンジンのゲームを
外で遊べるシロモノだ！
へぇ
Anyway, could you please quickly write up
your apology and leave?
とにかく早く反省文書いて
出てほしいんだけど
あ はい
Oh, sure.
（ガタ）
書かなくていいの？
Don't you have to write it?
It's fine.
いいのいいの
書かないで帰った反省文を
書けばお咎め無しだ
I'll just write another apology,
apologizing that I didn't write it.
ふんー
（吹雪の音）
No way...
ウソでしょ？
どうしよう
傘なんてないよ…
I don't even have an umbrella...
矢口くんを待ってたせいだ…
This is all because I waited
for Yaguchi...
（歩く音）
ギエー
この吹雪の中帰るなんて
ちょっと無理があったかな
Might've been pushing it
trying to get home in this blizzard...
（春雄）おーい
（小春）うん？
Hey!
"戸塚(とつか)商店"
こっちだ日高ー
Over here, Hidaka!
"戸塚(とつか)商店"
矢口くん？
Yaguchi?
（静かな音楽）
ここ矢口くんち？
Is this your house?
ちげぇよ
行きつけの駄菓子屋だ
Nope. It's my favorite candy shop!
買い食いする時とか
雨宿りする時に
I come here a lot to buy snacks
or for shelter when it rains.
よく使わせてもらってんのさ
駄菓子屋って
来るの初めてかも…
I think it's my first time
inside a candy shop.
Are you serious?
マジかよ？
It's nice and warm...
あったかい
ま 俺がここへ来る
一番の理由はこれだけどな
Well, this is the main reason
I come here.
見よ これが
「スト２ダッシュ」だ
Here we have
Street Fighter II: Champion Edition!
スリーが出るかと思ったら
ダッシュだもんな
Just as we thought the third one would
come out... Champion Edition!
で次こそはと思ったら
ダッシュターボが出てきてな
Next has to be "III", right?
But it's Turbo: Hyper Fighting!
そうこうしてるうちに
スーパーが出て
Meanwhile, they're releasing
The New Challengers...
ここまで来ると
スト２の奥の深さに
Now, surely, you must appreciate
the depth of Street Fighter II!
感服せざるを得ねぇ
何言ってるのか
全然分からない…
I have absolutely no idea
what's he's on about.
おばちゃんが
スーパーを入れてくれたら
Now, if Granny would just get The New
Challengers here I'd have no complaints!
文句無しだったのにな
ワガママ言いなさんな
Always so demanding, aren't you?
さてと…
All right.
さっき日高にスト２ダッシュ
邪魔されたモヤモヤ
Time to clear this fog that's appeared
since you interrupted my game
ここで解消させてもらうぜ！
in Champion Edition
just now!
私 悪者？
So it's my fault?
それより学校帰りに
ゲームなんていいの？
Should you really be playing games
on the way home from school?
かってぇ事言うなよ
Don't get preachy with me.
むしろ皆は家帰って
何やってんのか
It's a mystery to me what other people
do when they're back home...
不思議で仕方ねぇ
日高は家帰って
毎日何やってんの？
What do you do each day
when you get home, Hidaka?
え…
I watch reruns of period dramas
with my mom...
お母さんと
「水戸黄門(みとこうもん)」の(みとこうもん)再放送観て
ニュース観て
I watch the news...
お父さんのお店少し手伝って
I help my dad with his shop a little...
勉強して？
I study...
ふうん
For me, before I leave the house
after I get back home,
俺は家に帰る前も
帰った後も
ゲームばっかだ！
it's all games!
He's proud of that?
いばる事なの？
Well, want to try it?
I'll treat you!
な ちょっとやってみるか？
おごってやっからよ
（カチッ）
え？
楽しそうな事は
率先してやってみねぇとな
You've got to go ahead
and try things that look fun.
遊びの幅も
広がるかも知れんだろ？
Who knows, you might find a new interest.
私がゲームにハマると？
Me, getting into games?
外は吹雪で帰れねぇんだ
Can't go home because of this blizzard.
暇つぶしにゃ
最高の遊びだと思わんか？
Isn't this the perfect way
to kill some time?
ええー
ゲームなんてした事ないよ…
I've never played any games.
（ゲームの音）
どのキャラクターにする？
Which character do you want?
I don't know any of them...
って聞かれても
ZANGIEF
へぇ
（ゲーム）
ラウンドワン ファイッ！
Round 01.
Um...
えと…
うー
こう？　あれ？
（春雄）
手元を見ながらの操作
She plays looking at her hands.
A typical button-masher.
典型的なガチャ作法
Sweet little rookie.
微笑ましいウブさ加減だぜ
なんでザンギ選んだんだ？
Why did you pick Zangief?
え…なんとなく
強そうだったから
Dunno, I just did.
He seemed strong.
（ゲーム）
ショーリューケン！
Oh, I can't do it...
うう できないよ…
（効果音）
（ゲームの音）
あ 何か技出た
Oh, I found a move!
スクリューパイル
ドライバーだ
The screw pile-driver.
ガチャ戦法なのに
よく一回転が出せたな
She's just button-mashing,
surprising she managed a full-turn move.
ド素人は昇龍拳(しょうりゅうけん)すら
出しにくいのに
Even shoryuken is tough for amateurs.
（ゲーム）
ユーウィン！
ハハハ！
Bonus: 4700
この人 すごい胸毛だね…
This fellow has some serious
chest hair.
ラウンドツー ファイッ！
あっ
ヘッドバットで
対空対処している？
Countering with a head-butt?
偶然にしちゃ
でき過ぎてるような…
It seems too good
to be just a coincidence...
うう…
不気味な奴だ…
What a strange girl...
- ショーリューケン！
- あ！
Oh!
うっ こいつ！
What!
矢口くん もう代わって
Hey, Yaguchi, can you take over?
なんか怖くなってきた
This is scaring me.
何がだ！
お前の方が怖ぇよ！
Huh? You're the scary one!
どうだ
クリアーしてやったぜ
How about that? I cleared it.
ザンギのエンディングは
Zangief's ending has him doing low-kicks
with some random old guys.
知らないオジさんと
下段キックをして終わるんだ
ゴルバチョフ大統領と
コサックダンスしてるでしょ
Isn't that President Gorbachev
doing a Cossack dance?
日高が
筐体のゲームやるなんて
If our classmates saw you playing
an arcade game,
クラスの奴が見たら
たまげるだろうな
they'd be blown away.
You may be right.
そうかもね
お 帰れそうだぜ
Oh, looks like we can get home.
（歩く音）
どうだったよ
カプコンクオリティー
How did you like it, then?
Capcom Quality!
俺がゲーセン通いの
バカになるのも分かるだろ？
Do you now get how
I became obsessed with games?
Well, I think I still prefer
watching from behind.
まぁ 私は後ろから
見てる方が好きだけど…
あの駄菓子屋な
That candy shop...
おばちゃんが年だから
もうすぐ店閉めちまうんだよ
It'll close soon, what with
that Granny getting so old.
おばちゃんの元気づけにって
毎日通ってたんだけど
I've been trying to stop by everyday
to cheer her up, but…
残念で仕方ねぇ…
It's such a shame.
（静かな音楽）
（小春）
そういえばね
Actually...
ああいうゲーム機械
昨日うちの店にも導入された
My dad just installed some
arcade games like that at his shop--
Seriously? What's on them?
マジで？
何があんの？
Um, I think it was Dynasty...
- えっと 確か三国志の…
- 「天地を喰らう」か
Wars?
- ヤンキーみたいな
- 「熱血硬派(ねっけつこうは)くにおくん」
Then something with a rebel...
Renegade!
-Then The Gen--
-The Genji and the Heike Clans! Amazing!
- あと源…
- 「源平討魔伝(げんぺいとうまでん)」
素晴らしい！
But they're outside,
and it's cold, so...
でも外にあるから
寒いんだよね
That's totally okay!
I'll be there every day this winter break!
全然へっちゃらだぜ！
冬休み毎日行ってやる！
そうかー！
So, that's it... My new oasis
will be Hidaka's place...
俺の新しいオアシスは
日高の家にあったか！
"Every day"...
毎日か…
あれ？
なんで私
Huh? Why...
Why am I a little excited?
ちょっと浮かれてんだろ…
"ハイスコアガール"
HI SCORE GIRL
（ゲームの効果音）
Where's this?
ここは？
滅びし平氏の恨み
忘れたわけではあるまいな
I hope you haven't forgotten
the grudges of the Taira clan.
え？
なんの事ですか？
Huh? Excuse me?
- ヒャッヒャッヒャッヒャー
- こ 怖い！
Yikes!
（春雄）
ヨッホーイ
Hey! Hidaka!
- 日高ー
- あっ
Yaguchi...
（効果音）
矢口くん？
（タッ）
よっと
いや まさか日高が
I never thought you'd find
this world interesting!
この世界に興味を
持ってくれるとはな
ここ 一体何なの？
Just what is this place?
Here? This is...
（効果音）
ここか？
ここは…
a good place...
いい所だぁ
Where are we?
どこかよ！
（タンタン）
痛っ！
Why are there tops coming
out of that gourd?
ひょ ひょうたんからコマ？
コトワザ？
Is it a metaphor?
なぁ 向こうの備前まで
行って虎を見に行こうぜ
Hey, let's head to that pot and
check out the tiger!
備前に虎がいるの？
絶対 嫌！
There's a tiger in the pot?
Absolutely not!
（効果音）
あひゃっ！
カエルはへばりついてくるし
A frog's sticking to me
どこからともなく
矢は飛んでくるし
and there are arrows flying everywhere!
（鬼）フハハ
（小春）今度は何？
Now what?
It's Yoritomo!
頼朝(よりとも)だ！
- ああ！
- うわっ！
"死"
DEATH
（ドサッ）
- うがっ
- ぐっ いったー
こ これは！
This is... an arrangement
of wicked wicker hampers!
つづらがつづらっと
並んでいる！
- さむ
- 違う
-How lame.
-No...
今のはナムコのスタッフが…
それより日高！
That was Namco's staff...
But forget that, Hidaka!
Our fate depends on your choice
of wicker hamper!
俺達の命運はこのつづらの
選択にかかってる！
え？
つづらの中にあるのは
生か死か
Does the hamper have life or death?
Listen, if you get death,
it's really gonna mess you up.
いいか 死を選んだら
身体はバラバラになるからな
ちょ 怖いんだけど…
That... sounds pretty scary.
（開ける音）
うん…
いいんだな 日高？
このつづらでいいんだな？
Are you sure, Hidaka?
It this the right hamper?
- はっ！
- 日高？
Hidaka!
（効果音）
ああ！
（鳥のさえずり）
夢？
A dream...
ゲームバカの
矢口くんの影響かな…
Am I being influenced
by that idiot gamer, Yaguchi?
（明るい音楽）
（騒ぐ声）
（小春）
クリスマス会？
A Christmas party?
（女子）
そう みんなで集まって
プレゼント交換会やんの
Yep! We all get together
and swap presents.
輪になってそれぞれの
プレゼントをグルグル回して
We form a circle, pass around
the presents we brought
ストップって言った時に
持ってた奴をもらうっていう
and when the passing stops,
the present you're holding is yours.
- 知ってる？
- うん 前もやったかも
-Know it?
-Hmm, I think I've heard of it.
-Haruo?
-What do you want?
- 春雄
- あ なんだよ
I heard the Totsuka Shop shut down.
戸塚商店 閉めたらしいな
あーそうなんだよ…
That's right.
予想より早く閉めちまった
もんだからヘコンでんだよ
I'm down in the dumps
'cause it closed earlier than I expected.
ならウチ来いよ
ファミコンあるぜ
Come round to mine, then.
I've got a SNES.
ファミコンって…
A SNES?
まーいいけどさー
Well, that's great, but...
世のゲーセンには
But all the arcades these days
have 3D virtual fighting games.
３Ｄのバーチャル
格闘ゲームが出回ってんだ
も少し心動く
お誘いはできんのかね？
I don't suppose you have
a more tantalizing offer for me?
（春雄）どうよ
（小春）偉そうに
-Let me hear it, Miyao.
-All high and mighty.
Once it's about games,
he acts like he's cultured royalty.
ゲームの事になると
上から目線の
殿様気分になっちゃうのね
"明日から冬休み"
明日からの冬休み
Winter break starts tomorrow.
"明日から冬休み"
学生という自覚を持って
But remember you're still students,
so don't lose your focus.
"明日から冬休み"
気を抜かないように
してください
誰かさんみたいに盛り場で
現を抜かさないこと
Don't lose your grip in degenerate places,
like a certain someone.
Got it?
いいわね？
（笑い）
（歩く音）
Farewell, Mr. Numata!
沼田先生さようならー
（中国語）再見
Ciao.
（宮尾）
春雄
クリスマス会行くだろ？
Haruo, you're coming
to the Christmas party, right?
俺と行こうぜ
Let's go together!
しつけぇな
行く行く行くってばよ
Stubborn, aren't you?
All right, I'll go.
（鬼塚(おにづか)）
ねぇ小春
Hey, Koharu. Are you going
to the Christmas party?
どうするのクリスマス会
行く…かな？
Maybe I'll go.
あらまぁ 付き合いの悪い
小春がなんとも珍しい
Now it's unlike you
to come and hang out with everyone.
もしかしてあんたも
宮尾くんとの性交渉が
Are you also plotting to boost your
chances at carnal relations with Miyao?
できる確率を
挙げに行く魂胆ね？
違うから
Um, no.
（ゲームの音）
あ 行け行けそこ！
Go, go! Not like that!
違うよ！
（歩く音）
-I'm home.
-Welcome back!
- ただいま
- おかえり
ゲームの稼働
いいみたいだね
Seems the games are doing well.
Sure is.
そうなんだ
It's proving to have been
a wise investment.
ゲーム好きの投資を
バカにできないと実感した
うちは酒屋で子供達とは
無縁だったから嬉しいよ
Great since kids never paid us
attention before, being a liquor store.
ゲーム様様だな
All thanks to those games.
小春も冬休みの息抜きで
やってもいいからな
You can also give it a shot
during your free time this winter break.
サービススイッチ
押してやるぞ
I'll hit the free-play switch for you.
冬休み毎日行ってやる！
I'll be there every day
this winter break!
（騒ぐ声）
あ…
（鳥のさえずり）
"日高商店"
HIDAKA SHOP
（タッ）
うん
（ゲーム）
バっーカめぇ
（母）
プレゼントは持った？
-You got your present?
-Yup.
（小春）
うん
ラッピングありがとね
Thanks for wrapping it.
小春がクリスマス会に
行きたがるなんて
I never expected you to go
to a Christmas party, Koharu.
去年まではイイって
遠慮してたのに
You'd always write it off before.
- 楽しんで来てね
- うん
-Have fun, okay?
-Yeah.
（ガタン）
（ガタンガタン）
（歩く音）
（ゲームの音）
え…えぇ…へっ
あ…
- 矢口くん
- あ？
Yaguchi?
- 口開いてるよ
- シュルル
Your mouth's open.
よう 日高
Oh, Hidaka!
この大勢だと
どうしても開いちまうんだ
That just seems to happen
whenever I'm in this mode.
ふうん
Hey, don't you have any chairs here?
なぁ
ここは椅子はないのか？
- ないよ 歩道だもん
- あ そう
-Of course not, it's a sidewalk.
-Ah, right.
じゃ アホ面を公共の場で
曝すのはやめとくか
Then I'll have to stop
exposing my zoned-out face in public.
これからクリスマス会なのに
The Christmas party is going to start.
こんな所でゲームなんか
やってていいの？
Should you waste time
playing games here?
It's not a waste of time!
なんかと言うな
なんかと
俺にとっちゃ
こっちの方が重要なんだよ
If it's up to me,
this is more important!
Must be nice, Hidaka...
いいなぁ日高
Having a game cabinet at your house...
家にアーケード筐体が
あるなんてよ
俺が店の息子だったら
If I were the son of a shopkeeper,
I'd play it non-stop after closing!
閉店後やりたい放題
やっちゃうぜ
I'm sure you would.
矢口くんならそうかもね
Truth is, since the Totsuka Shop closed
実は俺 途方にくれてたんだ
戸塚商店
たたんじまったからよ
I've been at a real loss.
でも 日高んちのおかげで
But thanks to your place,
I can play games nearby again!
また家の近所で
ゲームができるから嬉しいぜ
近いんだ
He's close!
でも俺みたいな
ゲーマーが通ってたら
But a gamer like me will be an eyesore,
hanging round here.
目障りと思うからよ
見かけても気使わずに
無視してくれよな
Just ignore me if you see me!
え…
なんで…
なんでそんな事言うの…
Why...
Why would you say that?
（ゲームの音）
え 何？
Huh? What?
あっ！
Oh!
（ゲーム）
なめてんじゃねぇぞ
"終"
GAME OVER
RENEGADE HIGH
"終"
あーやられちまった
Ah, he got me!
しゃーねぇな なんだっけ？
クリスマスパーティー？
Too bad. Now, what was it?
That Christmas thing?
Shall we go together?
- 一緒に行く？
- うん
Sure!
（効果音）
うおーい！
Hey!
スト２シリーズの最新作
Behold, the latest
in the Street Fighter II series
「スーパーストリート
ファイター２」を入荷したぞ
Super Street Fighter II:
The New Challengers!
It's just arrived!
The... The New Challengers!
スー！　スパ２ー！
おや？
小春のクラスメートかね？
Oh, are you Koharu's classmate?
Yes! Um, could you let me witness
the installation of that cabinet board?
はい あの…
その基板を筐体に差す
所を見せてください！
いいぞ ブスーッて
差す所を見せてやろう
Sure thing!
Watch me plug the thing in!
（ガチャ）
はぁ…
（春雄）
あ…ああーっ
はぁはー
Woah...
すげぇ…
すげぇよ
Incredible!
何書いてんのか
全然分かんねぇけど
No clue what this text says
but I know this is something special!
すげぇことだけは分かる
何を見せてくれるんだ俺に
Just what will you show me?
（ゲームの音）
どこがスーパーなんだ
お！
What's "super" about it?
Ryu's in the opening!
オープニングは
リュウじゃねぇか
前回はよく分かんない
外国人が二人だったから
The last game had two random foreigners
ここもスーパーってことだな
so this part is pretty super, too.
Such pretty colors! Looking good, Ryu!
おー色綺麗だな
かっこいいなリュウ
What's-- Oh, there it is!
Hadouken!
なに お おぉ！
（効果音）
お はどうけん出たこれー！
あ！　スーパー？
Super...
おっ スーパー？
Super!
Super Street Fighter II!
「スーパー
ストリートファイター２」！
来たー！
It's here!
おー 見ろ！
一番乗りだぜ！
Look! I get to christen the thing!
（タン）
悪ぃな日高
Sorry Hidaka, The New Challengers is
more important than the Christmas party.
クリスマスパーティーより
スト２の方が大切だわ！
元々あんま行く気なかったし
I didn't really want to go
in the first place.
すまんが一人で行ってくれ
Sorry, but you'll have to go
by yourself.
（ブルル）
（ボタンの音）
- 私も行くのやめようかな
- え？
Maybe I'll not go either.
What?
（バシ）
あぁちょっ！
あぁ じゃあ
もう50円あるからやるか？
I've got another 50 yen
if you want to have a go.
大丈夫
後ろで見てる方が好き
It's fine.
I prefer watching from behind, anyway.
すごいね 最近のゲームって
Aren't games amazing these days?
だろ？
Right?
ウヒヒヒ！
ウィーヒヒヒ！
アーウー
ていうか本当にいいのか？
クリスマスパーティー
So are you really sure
about the Christmas party?
Yeah. I wasn't really up for it.
うん 私も
乗り気じゃなかったし
家でのんびりしてる
方が好き
I prefer relaxing at home.
まったく同意だぜ
I'm exactly the same.
よく殻に閉じこもってるって
言われるけど
People often say I'm too holed up
in my own shell
俺はそうは思わねぇ
but I don't think that's true.
（効果音）
逆に重い殻から
飛び出せるっていうかな
On the contrary, I feel like I'm leaving
my heavy shell when at home.
自分の意志に
忠実に生きるのも
I feel like I can stay true to myself
身軽で気持ちのいい
生き方ってもんよ
and live truly carefree that way.
だから矢口くんは
いつも楽しそうなんだね
So, that's why you always
look like you're having fun.
お前は窮屈そうだよな
You're just too stiff.
あんまり遊びも
知らねぇみてぇだし
You don't know how to have fun.
う…
じゃあなんとかしてよ
矢口くん
Then do something about it, Yaguchi.
へ？
実はね 私にも
やりたいゲーム…
There's actually a game
that I've been wanting to play
ていうか
見たいゲームがあって
or rather, wanting to watch.
「セプテントリオン」て
奴なんだけど
It's called SOS.
Also Otogiriso!
あと「弟切草(おとぎりそう)」
でも私 ちゃんとできるか
分からないから
But I don't know if I'll be able
to play them well.
矢口くんがやってるとこ
見せてくれたら…
If I saw you play it, maybe--
Nope. Do it yourself.
- やだ 自分でやれ
- えっ
はなっから
諦めてどうすんだ
You can't give up before you start.
やってどうしても
ダメな時に俺に言え
Try it, and if you  can't do it,
let me know.
そん時は俺がビシッと
手本 見したるからよ
If that's the case, I'll jump right in
and show you how it's done.
（ゲーム）うあ…
（春雄）あ！
あっ死んだ
I died...
（タッ）
ま こんなトコかな
Well, I guess that's that.
See you later, Hidaka.
じゃあな日高
（歩く音）
（車の音）
Wait, Yaguchi!
- 待って 矢口くん
- あ？
（静かな音楽）
Here...
（カサ）
これ クリスマス会の
交換プレゼント
A present, for the exchange
at the Christmas party.
- 私達サボっちゃったし
- ああ
Since we missed it.
Could I have... yours, Yaguchi?
矢口くんの…
それちょうだい
じゃあ
Well... here.
（カサ）
はい
- 中身なに？
- 手袋
What's inside?
Gloves. I made them myself.
自分で作って
お母さんに
ラッピングしてもらったの
My mom wrapped them for me.
へーすげぇ
Wow...
ちょうどよかった
This works fine.
If you play games in this wind...
この吹きさらしの中で
ゲームする時
手がかじかむから
your hands would freeze.
あーでも手袋しながらだと
操作性が若干狂うんだよな…
Yeah, but if I play with gloves on,
I can't play as well.
寒くて指が
硬くなるよりかはマシでしょ
It's better than your fingers
getting stiff from the cold.
- うん…うん？
- あ
Yeah...huh?
なぁ お前
すごく赤いけど大丈夫か？
Hey, you're really red...
Are you okay?
え？　そう？
Oh, I am?
（ピピピッ）
（小春）
ケホッケホッ
Thirty-eight degrees!
（母）
38度！
せっかくの冬休みなのに
And it's finally your winter break...
風邪なんて引いて
もったいない…
It'll go to waste
now that you've caught a cold.
いいの
It's fine.
♪10カウントで終わる♪
♪世界はモノクロだった♪
エンディングテーマ
'放課後ディストラクション'
♪朝の鍛錬
いちにのさんしで♪
♪ゴーゴー学校
コケコッコー♪
♪ＮＡＳＡの陰謀
しのごの言わずに♪
♪東京観光 大統領♪
♪登下校は高級車で♪
♪挨拶はごきげんよう♪
♪ジョン・レノンは
殺されたの♪
♪退屈な授業
エスケープ気取って♪
♪10カウントで終わる♪
♪はずだった
世界が色づく♪
♪エンカウントで
コンティニュー♪
♪小さな革命だった♪
♪放課後♪
♪ディストラクション♪
Subtitle translation by
Helen O'Horan
（春雄）
洋ゲーってさ
"「メトロクロス」
1985年アーケード稼働
株式会社バンダイ"
Western games, well...
"「メトロクロス」
1985年アーケード稼働
株式会社バンダイ"
They do have their own special appeal,
compared to Japanese games!
"「メトロクロス」
1985年アーケード稼働
株式会社バンダイ"
日本のゲームに比べて
独特の魅力があるんだよな
"「熱血硬派
くにおくん」
1986年アーケード稼働"
"「熱血硬派
くにおくん」
1986年アーケード稼働"
"「熱血硬派
くにおくん」
1986年アーケード稼働"
日本人じゃ到底考え
付きそうもないセンスとか
Like styles that
the Japanese would never think of...
日本人じゃ到底考え
付きそうもないセンスとか
"アークシステム
ワークス株式会社"
and design choices
they wouldn't dream of making.
"アークシステム
ワークス株式会社"
ウケそうもないチョイスを
わざわざしてくる感じ
"「源平討魔伝」
1986年アーケード稼働
株式会社バンダイ"
"「源平討魔伝」
1986年アーケード稼働
株式会社バンダイ"
Aw, now I want to play some!
"「源平討魔伝」
1986年アーケード稼働
株式会社バンダイ"
あぁ やりたくなってきたー
♪10カウントで終わる♪
♪はずだった
世界が色づく♪
♪エンカウントで♪
"日本語字幕 パク・スミン"